

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

I'm a passionate and curious web developer, who loves living in the "bleeding edge" and keeping up to date with the latest and greatest in the industry.

My mission is to leave a mark and contribute in delivering awesome web experiences that users love.

I love to write code. But I also love to keep it clean and tidy, reusable and documented. It's not just a skill, it's a testament of love for the project and your colleagues.

SKILLS RECAP

Front-End & Back-End

HTML5, CSS3 (+ Bootstrap, Tailwind), JavaScript ES6+, TypeScript, React (+ Redux Toolkit, Zustand, Router), Next.js 12+. HTML templating engines (ejs, isml), Node.js, Express, SQL, NoSQL, ORM (+ Prisma, Sequelize),

General or non strictly web-related skills

Agile workflow, Git (+ hosting platforms: GitHub, GitLab, BitBucket), basic Linux (+ WSL2), Rust, WebAssembly

CONTACTS

Phone: +39 351 9966 861

E-mail: viscuso.fabio@outlook.it

Address: via Salvo D'Acquisto, 5 95022 - Aci Catena (CT)

Website: fabioviscuso.it

LinkedIn:

linkedin.com/in/fabiocarmelomaria viscuso/

GitHub: github.com/FabioViscuso

WORK EXPERIENCE

WEB DEVELOPMENT INTERNSHIP

Deloitte Digital - Commerce (Nov 2022 - May 2023)

Hands-on approach on the Salesforce Commerce Cloud platform. The project I worked on was based on the SFRA, which uses a common stack that comprises CSS (custom SASS + Bootstrap), JS/jQuery and isml as the HTML templating engine. E2E testing was made using CodeceptJS and Selenium WebDriver. Jira and Confluence were the default tools used to manage tasks and documentation.

In my day-to-day I contributed to both bugfixing and features integration, especially regarding end-user QoL but sometimes also related to business logic and third party integrations.

WEB DEVELOPMENT INTERNSHIP

SEO Tester Online (Nov 2019 - Gen 2021)

First work experience in the web development industry. Aside from the basic stack, I also learned about:

- Docker
- VirtualBox + Vagrant, Windows Subsystem for Linux 2
- CMS: Magento & WordPress

In the first part of my internship I worked on some sibling e-commerce websites, helping in the bugfixing and refactoring. In the second part I implemented the website for STO's parent company in cooperation with the UI/UX designer. Then I spent the last months In developing a SERP preview tool prototype for internal use.

EDUCATION AND LEARNING

DEVELHOPE

Full-Stack developer bootcamp (React + Node.js) (Feb 2022 - Set 2022)

6-months duration coding bootcamp, focused on learning the following technologies:

- Git, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript ES6, React 18 & Redux, TypeScript, Node.js 16+, Express 4, elements of SQL Databases
- Agile/SCRUM Workflow, teamwork (I also had the opportunity to lead my team for two projects)

Aside from the course, I've explored hosting platforms such as Vercel, Netlify, Heroku, and AWS (RDS service)

UNIVERSITA' DEGLI STUDI DI CATANIA

Computer Science course - 2 years. without degree

LICEO SCIENTIFICO GALILEO GALILEI (CATANIA)

Graduated in 2011